Never forget why you are the church.
Go ahead and turn your Bibles to Romans chapter 11.
Thank you, worship team.
Get the worship team a hand real quick.
There you go.
And thank you, AV team, and give the AV team a hand as well.
Thank y'all back there in the corner.
Yeah?
Listen, we got things going on here.
You know, people, they call, they say,
well, you're off the beaten path.
No one knows that you're here.
Well, once they know, I pray that we give them some.
Amen.
So last week we finished up chapter 10.
And this morning, we're going to move right along in chapter 11.
And so go ahead and put on your preaching caps on because
we're going to get a lot of scripture in today.
Paul here is clarifying some of the troubling statements he has
previously made regarding Israel's rejection of Christ and
the hardening of their hearts.
He begins this chapter with yet another question.
I don't know if you've noticed or not, but the way Paul teaches
and writes his letters, especially in Romans.
It's kind of like a question answer format.
Right?
He knows what they're thinking.
He knows because he's a Jew himself.
He understands the mindset, so he asks questions
that he knows they're asking at least in their minds.
So Romans 11, verse one.
I say them, hath God cast
away his people.
Has God rejected His people.
Why does this matter so much?
You might be thinking right now,
Why would we go through verses one and 10 if he's
specifically talking to the Jewish community?
to the nation of Israel?
Well, I'll have you know this morning that if God can break his promise
to Israel, he can break his promise to us,
But God doesn't break promises.
Amen?
So we got to understand this for ourselves as well.
So this is important how we understand God's dealing
with Israel is critical to the rest of scripture, especially
here in Romans 11.
That being said, it is still some difficult truths that we're going to have to get over.
And remember that what the apostle Peter said about the writings of Paul.
I would say Peter's a pretty smart fellow himself.
He said, some of the things that he writes and teaches are just simply
difficult to understand, and it's no different today.
So we're going to dive right into it.
If you're there in Romans chapter 11, we're going to read verses
one through 10, everyone say, read.
I say that hath God cast away his people.
God forbid.
For I also am an Israelite of seed of Abraham, the tribe of Benjamin.
God hath not cast away his people, which he
forenew, what ye not, what the scripture saith, of
Elijah, how he maketh intercession, the God against Israel,
saying, Lord, they have killed thy prophets,
and dig down thine altars, and I am left alone, and they seek my life.
But what saith the answer of God unto him?
I have reserved to myself 7000 men who
have not bowed in thee to the image of Baal.
Even so, then at this present time.
Also, there is a remnant according to the election of grace.
And if by grace, then it is no more of works, otherwise grace
is no more grace, but if it be of works, then it
is no more grace, otherwise work is no more work.
What then Israel hath not obtained that which he seeketh for.
But the election hath obtained it.
And the rest were blinded.
According as it is written, God hath given them the spirit of
slumber, eyes that they should not see, and ears that they should
not hear unto this day.
And David said, let their table be made a snare, and
a trap, and a stubborn block, and a recompensing to them.
Let their eyes be darkened that they may not see and
bow down, they're back, always.
Romans chapter 11.
we're going to look at the theme, how unsearchable.
Here in God's word.
Let's pray, Father, I thank you, Lord, for this morning.
I thank you, God.
God, you are worthy of it all.
So God, I pray, Lord, that as I preach your word, God, anoint me for this time
to preach with power, clarity, and liberty.
God, I pray those that have ears to hear, may they hear, Lord.
And God, we thank you that you are not just a promised maker,
but the promise keeper.
And it's in Jesus name, you pray.
Everybody said, amen.
Now there was some obvious doubt from those who had heard this letter.
Now, remember how Paul ended Romans chapter 10 in
verse 21 of Romans 10.
But to Israel, he said, all day long, I
have stretched forth my hands unto a disobedient and
gainsaying people.
Listen, that does not sound too good.
As a matter of fact, you got to think about it.
As a parent, right?
And you get on your kids all day, all day.
You're correcting them all day, right?
And at the end of the night, you're like, you know what?
I have corrected you and had patience with you all stinking day.
Here comes the punishment.
Well, this is what God is doing right here.
So Paul yet again poses a question in order to
answer it correctly.
Again, I say then verse one, hath God cast
away his people.
Has God broken his promise?
Has Israel gone too far?
Has God responded to Israel's rejection by rejecting them as well?
And Paul emphatically answers immediately the same verse,
God forbid.
The NSB 95 renders this as may it never be.
And he then explains through examples how God still saves
those who put their faith in him.
His 1st example was himself.
Romans 11, verse one says this.
I say then hath God cast away his people, God forbid.
For I also am an Israelite.
of the seed of Abraham, of the tribe of Benjamin.
He gives the example of himself.
If God had rejected Israel, Paul
would have had no hope either.
I mean, look at his resume.
He was an Israelite, a direct seed of Abraham of
the tribe of Benjamin, although the tribe of Benjamin
was a smaller tribe, it was very much so a significant tribe.
As a matter of fact, Israel's 1st king was of
the tribe of Benjamin.
In Philippians chapter 3, verse 4 through 7.
We see even more his credentials.
Look at this, though I might also have confidence in the flesh,
if any other man thinketh that he hath whereof, he might trust
in the flesh, I the more.
In other words, listen, I have a resume that I can trust him.
Circumcised the 8th day of the stock of Israel,
of the tribe of Benjamin, a Hebrew of the Hebrews,
as touching law, a Pharisee, concerning zeal,
persecuting the church, touching the righteousness which is in
the law, blameless.
Listen, Paul was as Israelite as you could get.
And God saved him.
If God could save Paul, He could save any other Jew.
He then mentions his the next example.
We're moving quickly because we got a lot of scripture to go through.
The example of Elijah.
Look at verses 2 through 4 and Romans 11.
God hath not cast away as people which he fore knew.
What ye not what the scripture saith of Elijah, how he maketh
intercession to God against Israel, saying, Lord,
they have killed thy prophets and dig down thine altars, and
I am left alone, and they seek my life.
But what saith the answer of God unto him.
I have reserved to myself 7000 men
who have not bowed the knees of the image of Baal.
Now, we got to get some context here.
By the way, I want to, I said it's Wednesday.
I want to say this this morning as well.
A lot of people.
They want to disconnect the Old Testament with the
New Testament.
They say, listen, hey, whatever's in the Old Testament does
not apply to the church.
And so we're not going to look at the Old Testament.
Yeah, well, look at creation and we'll pick and choose stories from
David's life and all the things.
But really, we don't have to worry about the Old Testament.
Can I tell you something?
You cannot preach the New Testament without
preaching the Old Testament.
Understand, this is exactly what Paul is doing.
He is quoting Old Testament scripture.
We cannot disconnect it.
So we got to make sure that we know all things.
So we're gonna be looking at 1st Kings a whole lot.
We're gonna get some context.
Elijah was a mighty prophet of God.
His prophetic ministry happened in the time when King
Ahab and Jezebel ruled over Israel.
These were 2 wicked people, especially
Jezebel.
But God was using Elijah in a mighty way, even in the midst of
wicked rulers who would rather have him dead.
Allow me to put a little side note here.
If we are waiting for a perfect situation to be used
by God, you may just live your life ineffectively waiting.
If you're waiting now for something, and this is what happens.
Well, when I get that job, when I
pay off that debt, when I when I get that house, when I
retire, when my kids get more established, then and can
kind of do things on their own, then God, then,
then I'll start serving you, then I'll start doing a mighty work for you.
There will always be something, no matter what phase of life you're in,
that will hinder you walk with Christ.
That's called the flesh.
That's called battling here on this earth.
If we allow it to, there will always be a reason not to.
People all the time, right now, you could have given a 1000 reasons
why you could have just stayed home or done something else.
Listen, that's never going to change.
People say, man, preacher.
You care about numbers, and you care about this, and you care about that.
And my answer is, absolutely, I stink and dude.
We're going to count every single stinking Sunday at every program that we do.
Amen?
That's just what we're gonna do.
Why?
Because if we have about 165 here this morning.
That's a great number.
165 people said no to
any distraction, and yes, to going to God's house with
God's people, to hear God's word.
That's what we're talking about this morning.
That's awesome.
We should be excited about that.
Maybe one day we'll learn how to clap.
Amen?
Man, oh, man.
Yeah, that's right.
That's right.
But there's always gonna be something that can hinder us.
Listen, we went to a daddy
daughter, date dance thing, dance night thing.
We danced to music.
And man, they were dressed up.
I don't know if you saw it on Facebook meant my little girls are so pretty.
And, man, I dressed up.
I had my pink and purple to make sure I matched both of them.
I had my socks on, I had their face on it.
And I'm like, man, this right here, this is what it's all about, right?
This is all that matters.
I even, my phone was blowing up, but I was trying to be
intentional about just, you know, being in the moment kind of thing, 'cause I'm really bad about being in the moment.
I'm always in everyone else's moments kind of thing.
And so, man, we get there, man.
This is gonna be the best night of their lives.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, man, we got candy, we got some cookies, we got some cupcakes,
we got lemonade, and we got a dance floor.
Like, there's nothing else that could be good.
Let me just tell you something.
So this is Ridley's, she's three.
This is Ridley's first little dance.
Me and River have already done it before, and so she's kind of, she knows the
layout and she's over there dancing stuff.
But man, if I could, if, if it wasn't Ridley
wanting me to hold her, because the DJ was too loud, I
was holding her, then I looked down at, at River, and she's sitting there doing
this right here, because she wants to dance with me.
And so then I put down Ridley, and then I'm, like, dancing with
River, and then, really, all of a sudden, like, they're crying.
And I'm like, man, what is going on here?
And so I finally just crept down to, and that's what I said.
And listen, I don't know how y'all do in these situations.
Maybe you're better than me.
Good for you.
Amen?
But I sat down, I said, y'all, come here.
I said, this is really fun, and man, I've spent a lot of money for this night.
I said, but if y'all keep on whining.
We're gonna go home.
And you know what they did?
They said, okay, daddy, never mind.
All I'm trying to say is this.
In the church,
We're serving in the church we're doing in the church, man, we're ministering.
There's always gonna be something we can pout about.
There's always going to be something that we don't like as good as something else.
We're always going to look at somebody, maybe getting attention,
that we feel like we should get.
Do not let that hinder us.
Do not let our circumstance dictate
our obedience to the Lord.
Amen, church.
There's your little side note.
So in Jezebel, she had just destroyed the prophets of the Lord.
Ahab gathered all the prophets to bail together
at Mount Carmel, and Elijah met them there, and there
was going to be a little standoff.
So in 1st Kings chapter 18, verses 21 and 22.
We're going to read all through this right here.
You don't have to turn there, you can if you want to keep up.
It should be on the screen, perfect.
And Elijah came unto all the people and said, how long haunt
ye between 2 opinions?
If the Lord be God, follow him.
But if Baal, then follow him and the people answered him, not a word.
Then said Elijah and to the people, I, even I only, remain
a prophet of the Lord, but Baal's prophets are 450 men.
So let's get let's get the story here.
Right?
Ahab and Jezebel, man.
They wicked.
wicked rulers of Israel at this time.
And so what they're doing is they're trying to destroy
and kill all the prophets of God because they're saying things they don't want to hear pretty much.
And so instead, they get all the profits of
Baal, 450 of them.
They go up to Mount Carmel, Elijah goes himself.
Listen, I'm just one man of God against 450
men of a false God.
Let's see what happens here.
And he proclaims to all the people there, hey, listen, make your decision.
Who will you follow?
Looks like the deck is stacked against them.
Unfortunately for the profit of Baal, the profits of
Baal, God is not intimidated by numbers.
Amen?
Elijah challenged the other false prophets, build an altar and
call on your gods to send down fire to consume the offering.
So they accepted the challenge.
First Kings 18, verse 26.
And they took the bullock, which was given them, and they dressed it and called on the
name of Baal from morning, even until noon, saying,
oh, Baal, hear us, but there was no voice nor any that answered.
And they leaped upon the altar, which was made.
Listen, they were from all day, they were calling out
to Bel, God or Bel, hear us, hear us, Bel, but
no answer, no response, not a voice.
It got so bad that Elijah basically mocked their efforts.
By the way, if you ever need a biblical reason to just tease and fun.
This is what Elijah did right here.
And it came to pass at noon that Elijah mocked them and
said, cry aloud, for he is a god.
Either he is talking, or he is pursuing, or he is
in a journey, or peradventure, he sleepeth and must be awakened.
In other words, you're saying, hey, y'all aren't loud enough.
Go ahead.
Your God might be taking a nap.
I mean, he got so bad.
There was no response to Elijah, like, what is going on?
So they upped their game.
They upped their game.
Look at verses 28 and 29, and they cried aloud and cut themselves after
their manner with knives and lancets till the blood gushed out upon them.
And it came to pass when midday was passed, and they prophesied
until the time of the offering of the evening sacrifice,
and there was neither voice nor any to answer nor
any that regarded.
Another side note here.
The world can exhaust themselves all they want, attempting to do it their way.
We've got all this philosophy about how to get to God and how
to have a happy, go lucky life.
Can I tell you something?
God will not regard any way but
Jesus Christ and Jesus Christ alone.
Think about that term, nor any regarded, literally means no
one paid attention.
So since that did not work, that was Elijah's term.
We're gonna read verses 30 to 38 right here.
And Elijah said unto all the people, come near and to me.
And all the people came near unto him, and he repaired the altar of the Lord that was broken down.
And Elijah took 12 stones according to the number of the tribes of
the sons of Jacob, unto whom the word of the Lord came,
saying, Israel shall be thy name.
And with the stones, he built an altar in the name of the Lord, and
he made a trench about the altar as great as what contained 2 measures of seed.
And he put the wood in order and cut the bullocks in pieces and laid
him on the wood and said, fill 4 barrels with water and
pour it on the burnt sacrifice and on the wood.
real quick.
Does water and fire mix?
Okay, so what is he doing here?
He's trying to make a point.
He's saying, let's dretch this thing so you don't think it's just some kind of magic trick here.
And so we do it the 1st time.
Then he said, do it a 2nd time.
And they did it a 2nd time.
And he said, do it a 3rd time.
And they did it the 3rd time.
And the water ran about the altar, and he filled the
trench also with water.
He basically made a little pond right there in the altar.
We're calling down fire from heaven, and he's making a little water source right there.
I mean, this is what he's doing.
And it came to pass at the time of the offering of the evening sacrifice
that Elijah, the prophet, came near and
said, Lord God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, let me
know in this day that thou art God in Israel, and that I am thy servant,
and that I have done all these things at thy word.
Hear me, O Lord, hear me, that this people may
know that thou art the Lord God, and that thou hast turned their
heart back again.
How long you think it took to say that?
Are y'all with me?
What did the prophets of Baal do?
All stinking day?
Just jumping around, screaming and crying and hollering, cutting
themselves and gushing blood out their bodies, but no one paid attention.
And then here comes the man of God.
God, show off your power.
Y'all with me?
Well, that gets me excited.
Verse 30th and the fire of the Lord fell and consumed the burnt sacrifice in
the wood, and the stones, and the dust, and licked
up the water that was in the trench.
Not only did God send fire to consume the sacrifice, the fire
from heaven, consume the sacrifice, the wood, the stones,
the dust, and licked up the water.
Church, we serve the almighty God.
Amen.
The one and only, the God who exposes all other false gods.
Now, I want to say this, and there's so many side notes, because if you've ever read one
Kings, there's so many sermons in this one sermon.
So I'm gonna try not to get too crazy with it.
But understand this again, man, they're calling to their God,
the prophets of Baal, and no one is paying attention.
You understand what I'm saying?
Have you ever been in a room of children?
I've been in a room with your children.
It's called Women's discipleship ministry.
Amen?
Yeah, but they're crazy.
Yes, even your kid.
They're crazy.
And they're loud and they're they're obnoxious and
they're and they run around and they listen, they they they act like kids, amen?
Okay, so in other words, listen, I've been in a room of kids.
And man, these kids have been hooping and hollering and jumping around.
And then all of a sudden, though, I hear a voice.
And I hear, Daddy.
And man, there could be 50 kids in there just running around and screaming and doing all things.
But man, all of a sudden I hear that work, and what do I do?
My attention gets caught.
And I turn and there's my little girl.
How in the world?
Can I do?
when there's so many distractions, so much noise, so much going on.
Why?
Because I'm her dad.
And so when she calls out to me, you know what happens, my attention is caught.
I turn to her and hear what she needs to say.
What does she need?
Hey baby, what's wrong?
What can I help you with?
Listen, God hears his children.
And you say all the time, well, does God not hear a lost person?
Listen, 1st off, God can turn his ears on and off.
He's God knew whatever he wants to do.
God could hear all things.
He knows your thoughts.
He knows your heart, but I'm telling you right now.
God hears and pays attention to his kids.
And so we see that here.
Well, how did those watching respond?
Well, verse 39, when all the people saw it, They fell on their faces.
And they said, the Lord, he is the God, the Lord, he is the God.
When God works, it is incomparable.
It is unmatchable.
It doesn't matter how much the world tries to replicate what only God can do.
When God does his work, that's a wrap.
In my in my Bible in a year study.
I had just previously read in Exodus about the plagues.
And you know, for a short time, pharaoh's magicians
could replicate what God did.
But it didn't take long for them to say, hey, this is of God.
We cannot replicate this.
So when the world tries to replicate what God does.
Listen, there's churches all over the place right now, right,
that are trying to replicate what God truly wants us to do and be.
They're trying to foster.
They're trying to falsify the gospel and make it the true gospel.
They're trying to proclaim something as true, that is really not
true or just a half truth.
God does not honor that.
Listen, when they saw this, they understood, whoa, whoa,
the Lord, he is the God, the Lord, he is the God.
They fell on their faces, and they worshiped.
So what about all the prophets of Baal then?
We're moving quickly here.
1st Kings 18, verse 40, and Elijah said unto them, take the prophets
of Baal and let none of them escape, and they took them.
And Elijah brought them down to the brook, Kishan and slew them there.
What a victory.
You talk about being on a mountaintop.
Elijah was used by God to silence and to slay
all the false prophets.
was able to show that faith, the faith that brought down
fire from heaven, turned the people to the true God, and then what?
Would you say he's on a mountaintop right now?
I mean, how would you feel in this moment?
Would you not feel pretty good?
You say, oh, I would just feel humble for God to use me.
Stop being so self-righteous, man, I'd be clicking my heels, dog.
They'd be a little bit pet my step.
Like, did y'all just see what God just did?
Look at this.
Once up, you cannot touch it.
You can't do nothing about this, right?
Well, here's what happened.
Ahab and Jezebel heard about this and they were not too happy.
Jezebel even promised to kill Elijah by the next day.
Now he just stood 450 to one.
and defeated through God, defeated the 450
And now he hears about some wicked woman that
wants him dead and he gets scared.
Instead of boldly continuing in the truth, Elijah became scared for his life and fled.
So God confronts him while he's taking refuge in a cave.
In the next chapter, 1st Kings 19, verse 9 and 10, and he came
hither into a cave and lodge there.
And behold, the word of the Lord came to him and he said unto him, what doest thou here?
Elijah.
Why are you in this cave?
And he said, I have been very jealous.
I have been very jealous for the God, the Lord God of hosts, for
the children of Israel have forsaken thy covenant, thrown down thine altars.
This is the quote from Romans 11, and slain thy prophets with a
sword, and I, even I only am left.
And they seek my life to take it away.
He felt alone.
He felt as though he was the only one in Israel who was following the Lord.
But God debunked that thought in the next verse.
Yet I have God tells him, yet I have left me 7000 Israel.
All the needs which have not bowed on the bell, and every mouth
which had not kissed him.
Now, I want to go ahead and preach the principle here because we're trying
to, we're kind of morphing too serious in one, but a lot of times in
our life, we experience something like Elijah did.
Just off the greatest miracle of his life, he becomes scared and discouraged.
And when that happens to us, we have to remember that we are not
alone, too many people suffer alone because
that is how they would rather it.
They would rather flee to a cave than ask for help.
They would rather stay in the cave than to look out and see the
blessing that God has provided for them.
Listen, if you don't hear anything else.
Get out of the cave of your life.
Amen.
But what does this have to do with Romans chapter 11?
Well, verse 19 and 1st Kings 19, again,
is what Paul quoted in verse three, Lord, they have killed thy
prophets and dig down thine altars, and I am left alone and they seek my life.
And what was God's answer exactly what he said in 1st
Kings 19, verse 18?
In Romans 11, verse 4.
But what saith the answer of God in the hymn, I have reserved to myself
7000 men who have not bowed the knee
to the image of Baal.
See, this preservation of the faithful remnant
is of Israel was a work of God.
Romans 11, verse 5, even so then at this present time,
also there is a remnant according to the election
of grace.
Here we get to an important doctrine that keeps coming up in Paul's
writing, especially in Romans.
He mentions the election of grace.
If you remember back in Romans 11, verse two, God
hath not cast away his people, which he forenew.
That's the word for in you again.
Remember, God is not a passive God.
He is full and active in every part of creation
and life.
His plan comes to be, hear me, because he works it to be.
He is not, he's not passive.
He is active.
Yes, there is a covenant between God and Israel.
I use the present tense because contrary to
secular opinion at the moment, God has not given
up or forsaken the nation of Israel.
That does not mean that we have to agree with everything Israel does.
Amen.
Just like we don't have to agree with everything our government in
the U, United States does.
There's this thing going around.
I know you've probably seen it.
I don't want to speak on it too much, but it is big
up and listen, if I got to, if I've got to
proclaim that I think that God created us all
equal and racism is bad, then I'm obviously not living my life
correctly, My life should be living that.
You understand what I'm saying?
And not only that, people say, well, well, this and that,
and if you voted for this guy, then you support,
listen, all I'm trying to say is this.
I'm not putting my faith in a president of the United States of America.
Now, listen, I'm going to do my civil duty and vote, and you should too.
But I can tell you this.
When, when, when Trump Farrells or Biden
Farrells, whoever is next fails, listen, you know why?
Because they're human.
And they have an evil nature.
If they don't know Jesus, they're living their evil nature.
I'm trying to say is this.
All I'm trying to say is this.
We don't have to agree with everything.
But this covenant God made with the nation of Israel is everlasting.
It does not end.
I caution you to not form your opinion based on someone off
of social media or the mainstream news.
Do not let them out study you.
You can consider opinions, of course, but God's word is
the final say of what is and is not truth.
I was talking to somebody this past week.
And We sharply disagreed.
That happens a lot.
I don't know why.
But anyway.
We were talking about church and how church should be, and it was funny
because, and good dude.
Like, I mean, we get along stuff, but I
was trying to get normal stuff.
I said, hey, man, you know, church, you like church and everything, he's like, no, I'm like, okay.
And so I was like, this is going to be interesting right out the gate, you know what I'm saying?
And he said, yeah, I just don't really like the whole thing.
Like, I don't really care to be a part of someone's life or then be a part of my life.
I just want to go to church, hear the word and leave.
Don't like be calm or text me or checking up on me or I
don't want to join a dumb life group.
I'm like, okay, yeah, we disagree, bud.
And he goes, okay, yeah.
So a few minutes later, he said, oh, by the way, what do you do for a living?
I said, I passed her church.
a Baptist church, like that right there.
And he goes, oh, we do this aggressive sharply.
But listen, what is sad is, and we had a conversation
and with people like this, I've noticed this.
either an experience, a personal
opinion, dictates their theology.
You understand what I'm saying?
Well, the church hurt me when I was a kid or teenager,
so therefore the church is just unholy and not biblical.
Well, listen, I'm so sorry you got hurt.
But your hurt does not change God's truth.
You understand what I'm saying?
Hang out a little bit longer.
You'll get hurt again.
okay?
That's just how hanging out with people are, okay?
All right?
If you've been married long enough, you know that, hey, listen, y'all can very rarely hurt my feelings.
I'm just going to let you know right now.
I used to be able to hurt my feelings, but now I'm just numb to life.
Amen.
But here's what I tell you.
Listen, here's what I thought.
You know who can't hurt my feelings?
This lady right here, right here in the front row, man.
She told me something last night, and, man, I thought about it all night.
I was like, man, that hurt my feelings.
So, listen, we gotta understand the closer we get, the easier
it is going to be, believe it or not, to hurt each other's feelings.
Why?
Because we care about each other.
We're living life with each other.
But I told him, I said, I said, listen, man, I said,
would you like to know what the Bible says?
He said, ah, well, now, I'm like, well, man, I have nothing for you then.
Listen.
We don't we don't get to come to God on our own terms.
You can consider, again, opinions, but God's word
is the final say of what is and is not truth.
People say all the time, Israel runs the world.
And I get it.
You can look up, you know, Jews own this company and that company, you never know.
Like, man, my goodness, they they do kind of run the world.
Well, how do you think that is even possible?
How can a small of a nation is Israel?
Held captive time and time.
Have you read your Old Testament?
That nation's been through it because of their sin.
I mean, they spread abroad and scattered throughout
all the earth, surrounded by enemies, no matter
where they were, and all of a sudden in 1948,
they become reinstated and nationally recognized as a sovereign nation.
How does that even happen?
Because God has an everlasting covenant.
Other nations have wanted them annihilated since Egypt.
Yet the small nation still stands and stands strong.
Again, I'm not trying to tell you the leadership of Israel is born again.
I'm not trying to tell you that they're fearing God right now.
All I'm trying to say is God keeps his promises.
An everlasting covenant is one that does not change.
But we have learned that even though there's a national covenant, not all Israels are believers.
This is where the remnant comes in.
Within the nation of Israel who's under the covenant
of God, there are those who have placed their faith in Jesus' Lord.
Paul uses the example of the 7000 men in
1st Kings to reflect those chosen by grace in his day.
Now you might say, well, hold on.
If just because they're Israel, does that mean that they're saved because
of God's covenant with Israel, God's covenant with Israel has
eschatological views about it.
God's end time plan revolves
around the nation of Israel.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
So in other words, that's his plan there.
But a Israelite, just like a Gentile
has to come to salvation through faith in Christ.
That does not change because God does not change.
So the remnant of those who God foreign you, those who according to
God's plan of salvation, put their faith in Jesus.
Paul continues his doctrinal truth in verse six.
And if by grace, then there's no more works, otherwise grace is no more grace.
But if it be of words, then there is no more grace.
Otherwise, work is no more work.
It has to be one or the other.
If you get saved by works, then there's no grace involved.
And if you get saved by grace, there's no works involved in
your salvation, although you show your faith by your works.
Now with me this morning, I told you we're going to, some things.
Paul is consistent in all his writings, but remember this about
Israel in particular here.
Verse 7 through 10.
What then?
Israel hath not obtained that which he seeketh for, but
the election hath obtained it and the rest were blinded.
According as it is written, God hath given them the spirit of
slumber, eyes that they should not see and ears they should not hear unto this day.
And David said, let their table made a snare, and a trap, and
a stumbling block, and a recompension to them.
Let their eyes be darkened that they may not see and bow down their back always.
Now.
How could someone seek after God and God not save them?
That's a pretty good question, amen?
I mean, that's, that is like the question.
Is this not contrary to Romans 10, 13.
It says whosoever shall call upon the name of the Lord, shall be saved.
I mean, if you call upon him and he don't save you, then
that scripture is in vain.
Well, let's not forget Romans 10.
Remember, we're taking a long time to
read a letter that was written in one sitting.
Are y'all with me?
So we got to put it all together.
That's why I should challenge you every week and I don't, but I'm challenging now.
Go and reread Romans.
Make sure you're continuing in the themes of knowledge and understanding
in this doctrinal letter.
So it says right here in Romans 10, 2, and 3, for I bear them record,
that they have a zeal of God, but not according to knowledge,
for they being ignorant of God's righteousness and
going about to establish their own righteousness, have
not submitted themselves unto the righteousness of God.
The Jews, nor I, nor you, get
to seek God on our own terms.
That takes all the grace out of it.
Our own terms.
If we could build a system of salvation,
it would immediately go to workbase because that's what it's been since
the beginning when we got our hands on it.
Think about it.
What does the average person say when you ask them if they're going to heaven?
Hey, you know the Lord?
Yes.
You going to heaven?
I hope so.
That's the plan.
Now, why would they say that?
Carlos asked me if I know Jesus.
Yes, sir.
And I asked me if I'm going to heaven.
Did you see what I just did there?
Some y'all need to say today.
Let's do this again.
Ask me if I know Jesus.
Yes.
Now ask me if I'm going to heaven.
Why?
Because those 2 things go together.
The Bible says you have Jesus, you have life.
You don't have Jesus, you don't have life.
So what I'm saying is when people, when you go visit and
witness to your coworkers and your neighbors and all the people in
a sauna every single day, listen, when you do that and they say, I hope so,
instantly what they're doing, is they're
replacing grace with works.
Why would you hope so?
If you know Jesus, what is there, what else is there to do?
Whether and if they're honest, they'll explain.
Well, I just, you know, I just hope that I do good enough to get there.
I just hope that I do enough.
I hope that my one good day-to-day gets me to heaven.
I hope the scale is just tipping my favor, preacher.
Can I tell you something they won't?
That's why you need an advocate in Christ.
See, their hope is based on being a good person.
And this is a tragic misstep spiritually.
And because they had a heart posture, rejection, and stubbornness towards the will of God.
Listen, Tom and Israel again, they are blinded, and we see this today.
You know we send missionaries to the Holy Land?
We send people from our country to
the nation of Israel to proclaim the gospel.
Why?
Because they rejected, therefore they've been blinded.
Their own pride has become a stubborn block.
They have rejected a chief cornerstone.
They are building their lives upon shifting sands.
Church, you do realize that most Jews are looking for the 1st coming of
the 1st coming of Christ.
We're looking for the second coming of Christ.
What about you?
What is your life built upon?
We sang it earlier in the service.
An idea of a savior that you have made up on your own, in your own pride?
It breaks my heart.
Listen, it irritates me and I do get a little bit fired up about it, but
it breaks my heart more when someone says, well, I got my own thing.
going with God.
No, you don't.
How arrogant are you?
You telling me that God has a plan for everybody
else, but yours is different?
Listen, bro, I've only been talking to you for 2 minutes.
that ain't true.
You are not that guy.
By the way, there are no guys like that.
There are no women like that.
There's no one like that.
Jesus said, hey, I am the way, the truth, and the life.
No man coming to the Father except through him.
You don't get to change that.
So what is your life built on?
Have you built it upon pride or Jesus Christ and Nazareth who lived, died, and rose again?
So that we could be saved from our sin?
Once again, how does one become elected by grace?
What a great question.
How does one become the elect?
How does one become part of the remnant?
By grace through faith.
God will never cast away.
Those who come to him by faith.
So what Hezbound eyes closed over this place.